<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Raj Shah</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:48:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:48:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dan Meyer Does It Again</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-ive-been-thinking-about&quot;&gt;What I’ve Been Thinking About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been traveling around the state of Ohio talking to teachers about how to improve math class. I demonstrate simple ways to spark curiosity, encourage productive struggle, and plan for meaningful discourse. Most teachers are eager for tips and techniques and ready to try them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They love that we do math problems together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end the most common question I get is, “Where do you find these great math problems?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants the magic bullet. Dan Meyer’s Three-Act tasks, Fawn Nguyen’s Visual Patterns, Christopher Danielson’s Which One Doesn’t Belong, Graham Fletcher’s XXX, and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s been bothering me is that I don’t believe great tasks are the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great teaching is the solution! The tasks are just a tool in our giant tool box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-dan-meyer-at-nctm&quot;&gt;Enter Dan Meyer at NCTM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently Dan’s been wondering the same thing. Why does a task like Barbie Bungie which virtually every teacher seems to love sometimes fail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In typical Dan Meyer fashion he walks you right through all the key points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;routine-vs-non-routine&quot;&gt;Routine vs. Non-Routine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jobs requiring&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;co-constructed&quot;&gt;Co-constructed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-stack&quot;&gt;Full Stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question
Estimate
Err
Recall
Compute
Verify
Undo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hazards-of-paper&quot;&gt;The hazards of paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when you try and script the lesson? Can you make Barbie Bungie into a worksheet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the problem if you make a student worksheet for students, it’s easy to fall into the trap of providing too much information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you purposefully left out some key information during the launch of the task. How are you going to provide that on a worksheet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key point is that the organic discussions that arise in class are so much more valuable in keeping student engagement high and allowing students the freedom to problem solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you put a graph on the worksheet for students to fill out? If so, you’ve turned the non-routine into the routine of plotting points. Who decided which variables are assigned to each axis?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/27/NCSM-Impressions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/04/27/NCSM-Impressions/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
